Guide to the Institute on the Arts and Civic Dialogue Archive 1997-2000 MSS 127 MSS 127
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 3: 2000
  - Subseries 3.3: 2000 Overview
    - 2000 Overview: Table of Contents (Box 10, Folder 830)
    - Artist Overview: Smith, Anna Deavere, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 831)
    - Artist Overview: Smith, Anna Deavere, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 832)
    - Artist Overview: Alfaro Luis and Aguilar, Laura, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 833)
    - Artist Overview: Barnwell, Ysaye, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 834)
    - Artist Overview: Harper, Francesca and Jefferson, Margo, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 835)
    - Artist Overview: Kennedy, Sheila, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 836)
    - Artist Overview: Martinez, Ruben, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 837)
    - Artist Overview: Roche, Suzzy, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 838)
    - Artist Overview: Scott, Dread, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 839)
    - Artist Overview: Williams, Patricia, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 840)
    - Artists' Projects, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 841)
    - Appointment Information, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 842)
    - Artist and Staff Positions, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 843)
    - Barker Center Floorplans, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 844)
    - Budget and Map of Sub-activities, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 845)
    - Company Management, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 846)
    - Contact Information and Schedules, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 847)
    - Core Audiences, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 848)
    - Dread Scott--Search for Assistant, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 849)
    - Dunster St. Tasks, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 850)
    - Financial Information, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 851)
    - Housing, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 852)
    - Menus, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 853)
    - Office Equipment, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 854)
    - Payments and Appointments, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 855)
    - Production Space, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 856)
    - Resumes, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 857)
    - Staff Meetings/Agendas June 12-June 16, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 858)
    - Participants, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 859)
    - Projects for Summer, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 860)
    - Northern Lights--Video, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 861)
    - Web Page Information, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 862)
  - Subseries 3.4: Appointment Protocol
    This small group of files were received as an isolated group and all concern the appointment of artists for the summer of 2000. The files are arranged by topic.
    - Diamond, Liz: Call to Artists Correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 863)
    - "Yes" List of 2000 Artist Applicants (Box 10, Folder 864)
    - Artist Finalists for Summer 2000 (Box 10, Folder 865)
    - Call to Artists, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 866)
    - "Thank You" to Applicants, undated (Box 10, Folder 867)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10, Folder 868)
  - Subseries 3.5: Artist Applications--Appointed
    Applications of the artists who received appointment for 2000, arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - Acosta, Julian, undated (Box 10, Folder 869)
    - Alfaro, Luis, undated (Box 10, Folder 870)
    - Alguilar, Laura, undated (Box 10, Folder 871)
    - Azeda, Hope, undated (Box 10, Folder 872)
    - Barnwell, Ysaye, undated (Box 10, Folder 873)
    - Bell, Mercy, undated (Box 10, Folder 874)
    - Bowers, Bill, undated (Box 10, Folder 875)
    - Campbell, Colin, undated (Box 10, Folder 876)
    - Caraway, Nancie, undated (Box 10, Folder 877)
    - Chae, Esther, undated (Box 10, Folder 878)
    - Coleman, Chad, undated (Box 10, Folder 879)
    - Cummings. Blondell, undated (Box 10, Folder 880)
    - DuPre, Lynette, undated (Box 10, Folder 881)
    - Fleschler, Glen, undated (Box 10, Folder 882)
    - Foster, Gloria, undated (Box 10, Folder 883)
    - Harper, Francesca, undated (Box 10, Folder 884)
    - Jefferson, Margo, undated (Box 10, Folder 885)
    - Kanakulya, Freddie, undated (Box 10, Folder 886)
    - Kennedy, Sheila, undated (Box 10, Folder 887)
    - Kondo, Dorinne, undated (Box 10, Folder 888)
    - Lake, Oliver, undated (Box 10, Folder 889)
    - Lee, Charlie, undated (Box 10, Folder 890)
    - Lichtman, Amos, undated (Box 10, Folder 891)
    - Martinez, Ruben, undated (Box 10, Folder 892)
    - Ping Chong and Co., undated (Box 10, Folder 893)
    - Ramirez, Sarah, undated (Box 10, Folder 894)
    - Reynolds, Todd, undated (Box 10, Folder 895)
    - Riddle, Kimber, undated (Box 10, Folder 896)
    - Roche, Maggie, undated (Box 10, Folder 897)
    - Roche, Suzzy, undated (Box 10, Folder 898)
    - Saul, Abdoulage, undated (Box 10, Folder 899)
    - Scott, Dread, undated (Box 10, Folder 900)
    - Tully, Patrick, undated (Box 10, Folder 901)
    - Warring, Stacy, undated (Box 10, Folder 902)
    - Welch, David, undated (Box 10, Folder 903)
    - Williams, Patricia, undated (Box 10, Folder 904)
  - Subseries 3.6: Artist Applications--Tentative
    These applicants passed an initial screening and include applications from people who did finally participate in the Institute. Files are arranged alphabetically by applicant's last name.
    - Arner, David, undated (Box 11, Folder 905)
    - Belluso, John, undated (Box 11, Folder 906)
    - Borca, Karen, undated (Box 11, Folder 907)
    - Bullins, Ed, undated (Box 11, Folder 908)
    - Canner, Elizabeth, undated (Box 11, Folder 909)
    - Catler, John, undated (Box 11, Folder 910)
    - Chuma, Yoshiko, undated (Box 11, Folder 911)
    - Collins, Mary, undated (Box 11, Folder 912)
    - Conway, Mary, undated (Box 11, Folder 913)
    - Cooper, Mark, undated (Box 11, Folder 914)
    - Crockford, Michael, undated (Box 11, Folder 915)
    - Davis, Joe, undated (Box 11, Folder 916)
    - Denes, Agnes, undated (Box 11, Folder 917)
    - Evans, Josef, undated (Box 11, Folder 918)
    - Fisk, Roger, undated (Box 11, Folder 919)
    - Fo, Dario, undated (Box 11, Folder 920)
    - Grubbs, Carl, undated (Box 11, Folder 921)
    - DeGarma, Mark, undated (Box 11, Folder 922)
    - El-Dabh, Halim, undated (Box 11, Folder 923)
    - Greenway, Greg, undated (Box 11, Folder 924)
    - Ho, Fred, undated (Box 11, Folder 925)
    - Hovland, Patricia, undated (Box 11, Folder 926)
    - Jacobson-Hardy, Michael, undated (Box 11, Folder 927)
    - Katz, Joel, undated (Box 11, Folder 928)
    - 127.0002, Strange Fruit by Joel Katz, undated (Box 11, Folder 928a)
      Video recording, VHS, JVC T-120SX (on box) T30 (on cassette) Strange Fruit--Sample Reel; RT 11:20, Produced/Directed by Joel Katz, undated.
    - Knaack, Donald, undated (Box 11, Folder 929)
    - Kim-Gibson, Dai, undated (Box 11, Folder 930)
    - Lacy, Suzanne, undated (Box 11, Folder 931)
    - Lewis, George, undated (Box 11, Folder 932)
    - Lewis, Victoria Ann, undated (Box 11, Folder 933)
    - Maroney, Denman, undated (Box 11, Folder 934)
    - Mason, Keith Antar, undated (Box 11, Folder 935)
    - McCallum, Bradley, undated (Box 11, Folder 936)
    - Mosakowski, Susan, undated (Box 11, Folder 937)
    - Neblett, Tommy, undated (Box 11, Folder 938)
    - Parris-Bailey, Linda, undated (Box 11, Folder 939)
    - Rahman, Aishah, undated (Box 11, Folder 940)
    - Rahmani, Aviva, undated (Box 11, Folder 941)
    - Speranza, Carolyn, undated (Box 11, Folder 942)
    - Swanson, Christopher, undated (Box 11, Folder 943)
    - Washington, Lula, undated (Box 11, Folder 944)
    - Wayan, Wija, undated (Box 11, Folder 945)
    - Xiang, Jin, undated (Box 11, Folder 946)
    - XYZ, Emily, undated (Box 11, Folder 947)
    - Yankowitz, Susan, undated (Box 11, Folder 948)
  - Subseries 3.7: Artist Applications--Rejected and Tentative Rejections
    The applicants were either rejected outright or invited to participate in the Institute in non-funded roles. Files are arranged alphabetically by applicant last name.
    - "Rejected" and "Invited to Partake Without Funding" Categories, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 949)
    - Abbondanzo, Annette, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 950)
    - Afro-Bradley, Henry, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 951)
    - Allen, Alistair, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 952)
    - Allen, Eddie, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 953)
    - Aree, Elia, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 954)
    - Atwood, Donald, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 955)
    - Azeda, Hope, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 956)
    - Banks, William Jr., 2000 (Box 11, Folder 957)
    - Barancik, Bob, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 958)
    - Benary, Barbara, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 959)
    - Bersley, Tracy, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 960)
    - Bissundyal, Churaumanie, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 961)
    - Blockstein, Mike, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 962)
    - Bobgan, Raymond, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 963)
    - Bower, Sam, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 964)
    - Brooking, Bertelle, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 965)
    - Brown, Guillermo, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 966)
    - Brown, Kirk, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 967)
    - Bulik, Robert, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 968)
    - Burgess, Martha, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 969)
    - Butler, Eugenia, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 970)
    - Carly, Lauren, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 971)
    - Cavalieri, Grace, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 972)
    - Cebulska, Marcia, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 973)
    - Chodhourre. Eugenia, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 974)
    - Chang, Anita, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 975)
    - Choy, Anita, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 976)
    - Chutiwongpati, Sarawut, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 977)
    - Coffing-Blain, Crista, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 978)
    - Cook, Kim, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 979)
    - Corbin, Jeri, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 980)
    - Cunningham, Al, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 981)
    - Cunningham, Kevin, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 982)
    - Cuomo, Chris, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 983)
    - Curran, K.T., 2000 (Box 11, Folder 984)
    - Dannenfelsen, David, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 985)
    - Davis, Eisa, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 986)
    - Davol, Sarah, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 987)
    - Denison, Hannah, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 988)
    - Dickson, Josie, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 989)
    - DiStefano, Joan, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 990)
    - Dominguez, Ricardo, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 991)
    - Driscoll, Mary, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 992)
    - Duncan, Alan, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 993)
    - Duffield, Margie, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 994)
    - Dutz, Bradley, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 995)
    - Echanique, Melisande, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 996)
    - Eder, Melissa, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 997)
    - Eis, Joel, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 998)
    - Farrell, Mia, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 999)
    - Fitzner-Atchison, Judy, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1000)
    - Flax, John, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1001)
    - Fox, Jonathan, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1002)
    - Franklin, Ife, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1003)
    - Friedman, Gary, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1004)
    - Frillman, Karen, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1005)
    - Gaiter, Collette, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1006)
    - Gallimard, Gwylene, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1007)
    - Giering, Jennifer, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1008)
    - Goggin, Nan, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1009)
    - Graham, Lonnie, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1010)
    - Gordin, Ain, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1011)
    - Greanier, Mary-Ann, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1012)
    - Greenfield, Elena, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1013)
    - Gross, June; Novosielski, Viesia, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1013)
    - Gross, Sally; Norvell, Patsy, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1014)
    - Gundersheimer, Lee, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1015)
    - Hakoshimanm, Yass, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1016)
    - Hamilton, Ann; Harper, Francesca, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1018)
    - Hammers, Dawna, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 1019)
    - Hardenbergh, Marylee, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1020)
    - 127.0003, Marylee Hardenbergh: Performance Art/Choreography, undated (Box 12, Folder 1020a)
      Video recording, VHS, Sony T-120. Marylee Hardenbergh: Performance Art/Choreography; includes four pieces: "Bobcat Dance", "Plant Dance", "A Dance for Peace", and "Bridge Dancing"; RT 15:36; undated.
    - Haycock, Brooke, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1021)
    - Heffernan, Maureen, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1022)
    - Henes, Donna, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1023)
    - Hill, Morton, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1024)
    - Hooker, William, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1025)
    - Horban, Jamie, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1026)
    - Houston, Sterling, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1027)
    - Houston, Velina, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1028)
    - Huisman, Frans, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1029)
    - Innevarity, Mermie, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1030)
    - Inuzuka, Sadashi, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1031)
    - Jackson, Homer, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1032)
    - Jackson, Shawn D., 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1033)
    - Jang, Jon, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1034)
    - Johnson, Stephanie, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1035)
    - Jones, Daniel, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1036)
    - Jones, Katherine, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1037)
    - Kalisher, Jesse, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1038)
    - Kalu, Uchechi, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1039)
    - Kaminsky, Sheila; Hedman, Norman, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1040)
    - Kamler, Richard, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1041)
    - Keefe, Moira, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1042)
    - Kelly, Nancy, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1043)
    - Kelson, Carolyn, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1044)
    - Kempe, Kelly, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1045)
    - Khaminna, Muhonjia, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1046)
      Contains one 3.5x3.5 diskette labeled as containing the artist's resume and statement of intent.
    - Kim-Gibson, Dai Sil, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1047)
    - Kingsbury, Lonna, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1048)
    - Kirkwood, Carla, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1049)
    - Klugherz, Alice Jane, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1050)
    - Krebs, Joey, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1051)
    - Kreitzer, Carson Sarah, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1052)
    - Krusczewska, Meg, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1053)
    - LaPlante, Skip, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1054)
    - Lark, Carol; Bernstein, Mary, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1055)
    - Lascari, Anna, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1056)
    - Lee, Belinda, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1057)
    - Leiven-Young, Mark, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1058)
    - Leonard, Xavier, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1059)
    - Le Schhorn, Dick, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1060)
    - Levno, Stacey, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1061)
    - Lodato, Victor, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1062)
    - Lowenstern, Michael, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1063)
    - Macafee, Norman, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1064)
    - Mack, Evan, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1065)
    - MacLow, Clarinda, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1066)
    - Mancini, Ogostino, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1067)
    - 127.0004, Let Us Put Our Minds Together Music CD, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1067a)
      Sound recording, compact disk, Let Us Put Our Minds Together by The Hawk Project; c1997, published by Yerry Music Publishing, RT approx. 50 min. Modern arrantgements of traditional Native American songs.
    - Mann, Chris, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1068)
      One completely unlabeled, uncased, compact disk interleaved in book.
    - Mannix, Edward, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1069)
    - Manriquez, L. Frank, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1070)
    - Martin, Dan, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1071)
    - Martinez, Daniel, undated (Box 12, Folder 1072)
    - Martinez, Thea, undated (Box 12, Folder 1073)
    - McGaughey, Stanley, undated (Box 12, Folder 1074)
    - McGruder, Jasper, undated (Box 12, Folder 1075)
    - McLoughlin, Cathleen, undated (Box 12, Folder 1076)
    - McNeely, Madeleine, undated (Box 12, Folder 1077)
    - Medley, Cassandra, undated (Box 12, Folder 1078)
    - Misurell-Mitchell, Janice, undated (Box 12, Folder 1079)
    - Mitchell, James, undated (Box 12, Folder 1080)
    - Morris, Bonnie, undated (Box 12, Folder 1081)
    - 127.0005, Race, Prejudice and Health Care, undated (Box 12, Folder 1081a)
      Sound recording, audiocassettes, Brand/type unknown. Race, Prejudice and Health Care: The Lessons of the Tuskegee Syphilis Experiment; set of four audiocassettes of a seminar sponsored by the Urban Coalition, Illusion Theater, and the Center for Biomedical Ethics of the University of Minnesota. Undated, running time unknown. Submitted as part of the application of Bonnie Morris.
    - Oson, Nadine, undated (Box 12, Folder 1082)
    - Morett, Maria, undated (Box 12, Folder 1083)
    - Mosley, April, undated (Box 12, Folder 1084)
    - Nava, Silvia, undated (Box 12, Folder 1085)
    - Newman, Jeremy, undated (Box 12, Folder 1086)
    - Nickeson, Sandra, undated (Box 12, Folder 1087)
    - Panek, Peter, undated (Box 12, Folder 1088)
    - Papadakos, Ana, undated (Box 12, Folder 1089)
    - Patricca, Nick, undated (Box 12, Folder 1090)
    - Perez, Rudy, undated (Box 12, Folder 1091)
    - Perry, Janice, undated (Box 12, Folder 1092)
    - Piazza, Michael, undated (Box 12, Folder 1093)
    - Pleasant, David, undated (Box 12, Folder 1094)
    - Pointek, Gregory, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1095)
    - Pope, William L., 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1096)
    - Quinlan, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1097)
    - Rainey, Bhab, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1098)
    - Raymond, Monica, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1099)
    - Reese, Charles, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1100)
    - Reese, Bob, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1101)
    - Reese, Venus O., 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1102)
    - Rho, Sung, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1103)
    - Robinson, Walter, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1104)
    - Rodriquez, Arthur, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1105)
    - Roetter, Joyce, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1106)
    - Rohret, Bernice, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1107)
    - Rolnick, Neil, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1108)
    - Rosen, Craig, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1109)
    - Ross, Kwame, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1110)
      Contains one VHS video cassette:, 1995.
    - 127.0038, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 1110a)
      Video recording, VHS, 3M T-20. Stages of Truth (Edited highlights from the feature performance) by the Sands of Time Dance Company; "Promo '95/Version II Final Cut", RT: 16:08, 7/23/96. Submitted as part of the application of Kwame Ross.
    - Rowland, Steve, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1111)
    - Ruiz, Roberta, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1112)
    - Sahl, Michael, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1113)
    - Saint Croix, Judith, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1114)
    - Sanders, Edward, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1115)
    - Schaeffer, Karin, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1116)
    - Schildhaner, Cynthia, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1117)
    - Schoenfeld, Howard, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1118)
    - Searles, Heather, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1119)
    - Shen, Janis, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1120)
    - Sherman, Pamela, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1121)
    - Shields, Alice, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1122)
    - Simon, John, undated (Box 12, Folder 1123)
    - Simon, Ken, undated (Box 12, Folder 1124)
    - Simon, Patricia, undated (Box 12, Folder 1125)
    - Simpson, David, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1126)
    - Singer, Beverly, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1127)
    - Smith, Andrea, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1128)
    - Smith, Trudii, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1129)
    - Sogel, Daniel, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1130)
    - Solomon, Jeffrey, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1131)
    - Soreff, Sasha, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1132)
    - Spence, Pamela, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1133)
    - Spieler, Sandra, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1134)
    - Stahler, Wesley, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1135)
    - Snider, David, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1136)
    - Sternberg, Wendy, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1137)
    - Sullivan, John, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1138)
    - Tanjuaquio, Paz, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1139)
    - Perrin, Carol, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1140)
    - Thorne, David, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1141)
    - Tomlin, Liz, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1142)
    - Trachtenberg, Barbara, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1143)
    - Turner, Jill, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1144)
    - Ukeles, Merle, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1145)
    - Uzuri, Imani, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1146)
    - Vallon, Jean, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1147)
    - Van Kuren, Ann, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1148)
    - Vega, Carmen, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1149)
    - Vitale, Julius, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1150)
    - Walot, Francoise, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1151)
    - Ward, Melody, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1152)
    - Ware, Kendra, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1153)
    - Webster, Carol, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1154)
    - Weinstein, Larry, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1155)
    - West, Liz, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1156)
    - Whittlesey, Lorraine, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1157)
    - Williams, Liza, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1158)
    - Wilson, Pamela, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1159)
    - Wise, Nina, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1160)
    - Wolf, Marc, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1161)
    - Wolper, Andrea, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1162)
    - Woods, Allie, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1163)
    - Wyrrick, Sharon, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1164)
    - Yathin, Nejla, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1165)
    - Yves, Mustard, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1166)
    - Zhao, Suikang, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1167)
  - Subseries 3.8: Artist Applications--Unknown Status
    This body of applications was preserved as a separate set of files within the IACD records. The series contains a large number of applications from artists involved with the Institute in previous years as well as others. Files are arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - Call to Artists, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1168)
    - Akalaitis, Joanne, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1169)
    - Arce, Elia, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1170)
    - Breuer, Lee, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1171)
    - Chong, Ping, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1172)
    - Conway, Merry; Pratt, Noni, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1173)
    - Cortez-Woolery, Reginald, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1174)
    - Diamond, Liz; Picoult, Darcy, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1175)
    - Gonzalez, Anita, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1176)
    - Goode, Joe, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1177)
    - Hoffbauer, Patricia; Sanchez, George Emilio, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1178)
    - Jackson, Homer, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1179)
    - Katz, Joel, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1180)
    - Kim-Trang, Tran, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1181)
    - Lanzillotto, Annie, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1182)
    - Mason, Keith Antar, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1183)
    - McCallum, Bradley, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1184)
    - Miller, Tim, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1185)
    - Mogul, Susan, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1186)
    - Negron-Muntaner, Frances, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1187)
    - Perkins, Merle, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1188)
    - Portillo, Lourdes, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1189)
    - Rhine, Dont, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1190)
    - Royals, Demetria; Gonzales, Anita; McCauley, Robbie, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1191)
    - Spiegelman, Art; Parks, Van Dyke, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1192)
    - Spotted Eagle, Chris, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1193)
    - Strom, Mary-Ellen, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1194)
    - Swados, Elizabeth, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1195)
    - Wright, Jules, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1196)
    - Wyrrick, Sharon, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1197)
    - Yearby, Marlies, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 1198)
- Series 4: Video Recordings
  The majority of these recordings are of performances of works from the IACD. However one recording is of the production of Anna Deavere Smith's House Arrest at the Papp Theater in 2000. Another recording, from the Massachusetts Foundation for the Humanities, bears an uncertain relation to the IACD. There are two copies of each recording, access copies for viewing are in subseries 1; archival copies are listed in subseries 2.
  - Subseries 4.1: Video Recordings Access Copies
    The videocassettes are arranged as received
    - Institute on the Arts and Civic Dialogue, 1999 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 127.0006)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-15 std, SP, RT: 11:00
    - Institute on the Arts and Civic Dialogue, Off-Line Edit, 1999 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 127.0008)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-15 std, SP, RT: 10:54
    - Anna Deavere Smith With Bill Barbeaux, Summer 1999 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 127.001)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-30 std, SP, RT: 35:00; summer, 1999.
    - Musical Prayers, Summer 2000, Tape 1 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 127.0012)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-60 std, SP, RT: 35:00
    - Musical Prayers, Summer 2000, Tape 2 (Shelf Media, Media 127.0014)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-60 std, SP, RT: 40:00
    - Public Art, Public Land by Judy Baca, Tapes #1-3, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 127.0016)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-90 std, SP, RT: 1:20:00, undated
    - High Noon, Tapes #1, 3, 5, 7, 9, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 127.0018)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-160 std, SP, RT: 2:10:00
    - Brandon, Tapes #1, 3, 5, 7, 9, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 127.002)
      Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-180 std, SP, RT: 2:55